Elisabeth Edrington, DC

Denver, CO ZIP | Phone: (303) 908-3926 | Email: edringtonDC@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://www.elisabethedrington.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/elisabethedrington | GitHub: https://github.com/edringtondc

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Arising Full Stack Web Developer who brings a wealth of experience from the fast—paced, competitive healthcare field to IT. Proven professional with a record of successfully managing projects and teams, and making critical decisions under challenging circumstances. Lifelong learner, with a desire to always improve.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages/Libraries: JavaScript, ExpressJS, ReactJS, NodeJS, HTML, CSS3, MySQL, Sequelize, Mongoose,

Handlebars, EJS, GitLab, NoSQL, SQL, PHP

Frameworks: Materialize, Bootstrap

Databases: MongoDB

Deployment: Heroku, GitHub Pages, Amazon Web Services, S3, Netlify

Version Control: Git

Software: MacOS, Visual Studio Code, XCode, Atom, Mocha, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Google Earth Pro

Actively Learning: React Native, Python, VueJS

PROJECTS

BrewTinerary:

Maps breweries for a searched location. Select and save breweries to create an itinerary for your trip.

- ReactJs, NodeJS, ExpressJs, MongoDB, BeerMapping API, Google Geocoder, Google Maps, Stylized Components, React-Strap
- Lead developer and designer
- https://github.com/edringtondc/Brew-Tinerary
- https://sheltered-ocean-66992.herokuapp.com/

RecordsDB:

Allows users to upload and organize records for public access. Designed and marketed for The Current, a local newspaper in Lafayette, LA.

- MongoDB, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Amazon S3, Materialize
- Backend Developer, Database structures
- https://github.com/edringtondc/records-db
- https://morning-bastion-24081.herokuapp.com/

Memory Game:

Grumpy Cat themed memory game. To win, you cannot click on the same meme twice.

- Created entirely with ReactJS
- Solo Developer
- https://github.com/edringtondc/memory-game
- https://nameless-sands-19428.herokuapp.com/

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Trilogy Education - Denver, Colorado

Tutor -Full Stack Web Development, April 2019- Present

- Responsible for providing tutoring for students outside of their regular class hours.
- Design and carry out and manage the scheduling of hour long tutoring sessions based on individual students needs.
- Topics include HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, API's, Node, Express, React, database structures and languages, setting up and navigating IDEs, understanding chrome developer tools, media queries, git workflow and commands, and using the CLI.

Boss Lady Web Design -Denver, Colorado

CEO/Lead Designer, January 2019- Present

- Lead designer, responsible for creating websites based on a clients needs, and delivering a completed product on time. Design, create, deploy and maintain MERN stack websites using AWS, GoDaddy and Netlify.
- Use Slack, Zoom meetings and Google Cloud Platform tools to communicate with clients and collaborators.
- Designing a templated Chiropractic Website, marketed directly to chiropractic practices.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

SRS Real Estate - Denver, Colorado

Marketing Coordinator, April 2019-Present

- Create, organize and design marketing materials for commercial real estate brokers, using Photoshop, Illustrator and Google Earth Pro.
- Manage web listings and digital brochures via Build Out and Costar real estate services.

Edrington Chiropractic, LLC - Denver, Colorado

CEO/Chiropractor, 2012 - Present

- As head Chiropractor, examine, diagnose and treat a variety of patients. Utilized electronic health care technology, scheduling software and client relationship management software to keep track of medical notes and patient communications.
- Solely responsible for client acquisition using local networking strategies as a well as professional referrals.
- Voted Best Chiropractor in Littleton in 2013
- Initialized, implemented and customized ChiroTouch Software into the practice, as well as providing training for support staff to use the program.

EDUCATION

University of Denver - Denver, CO *Certificate, Full Stack Web Development*

Logan College of Chiropractic - Chesterfield, MO

Doctor of Chiropractic

Logan University- Chesterfield, MO *Bachelor's of Science - Life Sciences*